<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="pretty-atom-feed.xsl" type="text/xsl"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Blog Title</title>
  <subtitle>This is a longer description about your blog.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://example.com/feed/feed.xml" rel="self" />
  <link href="https://example.com/" />
  <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
  <id>https://example.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name>Your Name</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>Loving Holiday Greetings &amp; Happy 2014! (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1236/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1236/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My first official update&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lovely tribe, what a year has it been! I smile as I reflect, for it has been an impactful year for me personally, with many life changing and &#39;first-timer&#39; experiences. Highlights include my first ever 7-day silent mindfulness meditation retreat, my first ever burn, my resignation from my 9-5 corporate career, my heart-charging experience at Awesomeness Fest, and most recently, my entry into a new decade - my good ol&#39; (young) 30&#39;s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I sit here proud of my successes, and motivated and driven to fly even higher in 2014, with focus, collaborations, and most importantly, balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My website is coming together, with recipes being added and organized, so you&#39;ll no longer have to sort through my facebook page albums when you&#39;re looking for something specific. I have a lot more in store for the new year, from coaching, to vlogs &amp;amp; blogs, to hangouts, to webinars, to recipe books, to marketable food products, to games, to retreats - and well, the list continues, and becomes clearer as my intentions and manifestations become stronger and more consistent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until launch date, I&#39;ll send you email updates, to fill you in on some of my most cherished milestones, and of course, to keep you in the positive loop. Since google has made some changes and updates, many &#39;mailing list&#39; emails are now being labeled as &#39;promotions&#39; and are not visible in the inbox. To avoid having this email fall into that category, and get lost in translation, it&#39;s important that you go to your inbox and search &amp;quot;label:promotions&amp;quot;, highlight my email (as well as others you may find), or search for &amp;quot;Living Rhea&amp;quot; and click &amp;quot;Not Promotions&amp;quot; at the top of the page. This will ensure future emails come to your inbox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Excited to journey with you, and continue to share my research, expeRAWments, learnings, insights and programs with you, in 2014 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Happy Holidays! Enjoy this loving time, and please join me in setting 3-5 solid intentions and goals for the new year, verbally, written and/or in the form of a vision board (tangible or virtual).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LOADS of love, light &amp;amp; warmth,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rhea xx&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Unhealthy habits? Learn how to create healthy distractions. (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/unhealthy-cravings-learn-create-healthy-distractions/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/unhealthy-cravings-learn-create-healthy-distractions/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Drink my Distraction Juice (not from concentrate).  It tastes like love, only not so focused on just one ingredient. ― Jarod Kintz&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>14 Health-Sabotaging Myths Exposed By The TOP Nutrition &amp; Fitness Experts (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be lovingly honest here…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are far too many “health experts” preaching so-called “health advice” that we are being led to believe is the Holy Grail of the “healthy lifestyle” dream we’re chasing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They are spoonfeeding you catchy claims like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“6-pack secrets they don’t want you to know!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Fat-burning formula to lose 20 lbs. in 7 days!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And best of all...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The limitless magic pill they created from a powerful ingredient accidentally discovered by a group of scientists in the ancient city of Timbuktu that will change EVERYTHING!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And unfortunately — &lt;strong&gt;we’re eating it right up&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you know the big problem with this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large majority of those “health experts” haven’t put in their 10,000 hours of research, have no evidence supporting the fictitious “beneficial claims” they’re promising you, and probably (not probably… definitely) care more about their social status on social media than they do your health and wellbeing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Basically, their “advice” is hurting you more than it’s helping you&lt;/strong&gt; — and sorry, but your dream bod will take longer than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-truth-you-re-seeking&quot;&gt;The Truth You’re Seeking&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to expose these myths… so that’s why I reached out to the REAL leaders in this industry and asked them ONE simple question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What’s the most sabotaging health myth you wish the mainstream world had not been exposed to entering 2016?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I expected, I received enthusiastic replies with the health-sabotaging myths &lt;strong&gt;they wish YOU knew&lt;/strong&gt;. They delivered well-supported claims that will finally debunk the myths secretly sabotaging your health, happiness, and excitement for living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you feel shackled to a life of confusion and mediocrity when it comes to health, then this article will set you free.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s begin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-jj-virgin-jj-virgin-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/1-JJvirgin.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F1-JJvirgin-242x300.jpg&amp;width=242&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 242w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F1-JJvirgin-242x300.jpg&amp;width=242&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 242w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F1-JJvirgin-242x300.jpg&amp;width=242&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;1 - JJvirgin&quot; width=&quot;242&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 1.) JJ Virgin — &lt;a href=&quot;http://jjvirgin.com/&quot; title=&quot;JJ Virgin&quot;&gt;JJ Virgin Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The so-called healthy foods that come loaded with sneaky sugar and often create food intolerances. I&#39;m talking about fruit-on-the-bottom yogurt, breakfast cereals, and less-obvious culprits like balsamic vinegar and marinara sauce. We have become better aware of things like coffee drinks, which a recent report found can contain up to 25 teaspoons of sugar, but people are less aware that sneaky sugars in so-called healthy foods can deliver a massive sugar dose that wrecks havoc on our waistlines and overall health...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I 110% agree with this comment by JJ Virgin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When something comes in a box or a package, it’s good practice to look for the nutrition facts label and look at two things: net carbohydrates and sugar. Net carbs = Total carbs – Fiber. This will give you an idea of the amount of sugar (glucose and fructose) in the product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the products net carbs are in the double digits with little to no fiber, you can expect a spike in your blood sugar. And the dreaded spike in blood sugar will raise your insulin levels — which is not good. We all have different sensitivities to sugar and insulin; some of us (diabetics) have lost our sensitivity to insulin altogether.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you notice your energy and happiness plummet throughout the day, there’s a good chance you’re eating more sugar than what your body can handle in any given moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;If you absolutely must treat yourself with a sugary beverage or treat, do it after you’ve worked out when your carb stores are low.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, try swapping the sugary food with something high in healthy fat; like avocado, coconut meat, or a tablespoon of unsweetened almond butter. High fat foods can cut cravings for sugar while satiating the body.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-neghar-fonooni-neghar-fonooni-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/2-Negharv3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F2-Negharv3-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F2-Negharv3-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F2-Negharv3-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;2 - Negharv3&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 2.) Neghar Fonooni — &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.negharfonooni.com/&quot; title=&quot;Neghar Fonooni&quot;&gt;Neghar Fonooni Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I would say the thing I&#39;d want the mainstream world to know is that you have more to offer the world than your body fat composition. I work with women all over the world who are struggling to reclaim their worthiness, because as a culture, we&#39;ve tied our worthiness as women so strongly to our appearance…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though physical health plays a key role in your life and stability over the long term, there are other factors that play just as important a role — if not more — in your wellbeing: your emotions and your mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to the media’s distorted and superficial image of health, we’ve booked a first-class ticket on the vehicle of vanity to attain happiness. But the truth is, when we develop a strong and loving connection with ourselves at our core, we naturally begin to treat ourselves with respect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Write a love note or affirmation to yourself and keep it somewhere you know you’ll see at least once a day.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you see it, read it out loud. I kept mine on my mirror for 2 years until the words naturally found their way into my conscious: “I am a heart-centered jedi warrior goddess of truth.” The other one I learned at an event I attended last year in Croatia called A-fest: “I am enough.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-robb-wolf-robb-wolf-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/3-Robb-Wolf.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F3-Robb-Wolf-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F3-Robb-Wolf-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F3-Robb-Wolf-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;3 - Robb Wolf&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 3.) Robb Wolf — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/robbwolf.com&quot; title=&quot;Robb Wolf&quot;&gt;Robb Wolf Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging health myth I know of is that you can get by on less than 7-9 hours of sleep per night. Sleep is likely the most important component of health, and lack of sleep will sabotage health, performance, longevity, and weight loss more quickly than just about anything I can think of.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most important myths to debunk in my opinion because not enough importance is placed on sleep.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep debt is very real — those hours of sleep you missed while staying up until 5am are still affecting your body today. Which means the more we skip sleep, the more sleep we need to catch up on... And the only way to pay it back is through sleeping more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sleep offers us many benefits; one of them being the fasting state (not eating any food for a period of time). In this state, your body and brain have an opportunity to rest, rebuild, and essentially “get rid of the garbage.” If that’s not enough to convince you, a recent study showed that less than 7 hours of sleep a night was linked to a higher risk of obesity, diabetes, heart disease, stroke, mental distress, and early death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Get access to bright light (sunlight) during the day to maximize blue light exposure, and as the sun goes down, gently detach from your technology.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you absolutely must use technology at night, buy some blue light goggles. This should normalize your circadian rhythm and get you back into a healthy flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;4-gunnar-peterson-gunnar-peterson-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/4-Gunnarpeterson.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-Gunnarpeterson-215x300.jpg&amp;width=215&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 215w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-Gunnarpeterson-215x300.jpg&amp;width=215&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 215w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-Gunnarpeterson-215x300.jpg&amp;width=215&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;4 - Gunnarpeterson&quot; width=&quot;215&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 4.) Gunnar Peterson — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/gunnarpeterson.com&quot; title=&quot;Gunnar Peterson&quot;&gt;Gunnar Peterson Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Lifting weights will make you big.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot to unpack here, as the situation changes depending on the amount of the weights, reps, gender, and your lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For women, it’s important that we know our muscles cannot be compared to men simply because of our differences in hormones; in particular, testosterone. Weight lifting is unlikely to make a woman “big” like most of them fear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Focus on its many benefits, like improved metabolism, body awareness, endurance and mental strength.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;5-mark-fisher-mark-fisher-fitness&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/4-markfisher.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-markfisher-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-markfisher-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F4-markfisher-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;4 - markfisher&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 5.) Mark Fisher — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/markfisherfitness.com&quot; title=&quot;Mark Fisher Fitness&quot;&gt;Mark Fisher Fitness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging health myth I see particularly in regards to fitness is that ‘more is better.’ For instance, the goal is to do an appropriate amount of training at an appropriate intensity for a given goal, not as much and as hard as possible…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The emergence of personalized health tells us that no two people are alike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all have varying needs and susceptibilities dependent on our own lifestyles, environmental factors, and genetic factors. Therefore, there is no one-size-fits-all solution for everyone. For some, crossfit is the best medicine, and to others, it’s yoga.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Start with a low hanging fruit health goal — be it fitness or food related&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Work on building it into your day as a new habit before moving on to your next goal. Once you have a few small wins under your belt, celebrate them, and then give yourself permission to graduate to a more challenging goal that seems right for you. Keyword: YOU (not “them”).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;6-darya-rose-summer-tomato&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/6-darya-rose.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F6-darya-rose-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F6-darya-rose-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F6-darya-rose-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;6 - darya rose&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 6.) Darya Rose — &lt;a href=&quot;http://summertomato.com/&quot; title=&quot;Darya Rose&quot;&gt;Summer Tomato&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The greatest health myth I encounter every day is that you need to sacrifice and deprive yourself to be healthy, and that if you had more willpower to do this, you would succeed. Nothing could be further from the truth. Instead of depriving yourself to be healthy, you must find healthy activities you enjoy so they can become habits, which by definition, don&#39;t require willpower...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Though I agree with this in theory, I do believe there is a window of discomfort that often follows a health reset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Particularly when one is experimenting with the avoidance of toxic triggers and experiencing symptoms from the withdrawal of those triggers. There is power and healing in learning to find comfort within the discomfort — and almost always — willpower is your primary fuel to do so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This uncomfortable process can prove to be transformative. Intermittent fasting is another exception to this, whereby the short-term deprivation can lead to life-changing, or rather, life-extending results. Compensating with a high-fat “bulletproof” drink during the fasting period may serve as a way to minimize the use of willpower and cravings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Work on small, realistic healthy goals to build up the momentum and motivation before tackling harder to reach goals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So while I agree that we must find activities and practices that we love in order to build them into daily sustainable habits, I do believe in the power of a small window of discomfort in opening up new channels to success and happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;7-kathryn-budig-kathryn-budig-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/7-kathrynbudig.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F7-kathrynbudig-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F7-kathrynbudig-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F7-kathrynbudig-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;7 - kathrynbudig&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 7.) Kathryn Budig — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/kathrynbudig.com&quot; title=&quot;Kathryn Budig&quot;&gt;Kathryn Budig Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“I wish people would understand that there is no single road or fix to good health. Take the time to find out what style of nutrition and exercise fits YOUR body and needs, and not necessarily what is trending or expected.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As personalized health tells us, we are individuals with our own needs, predispositions, and sensitivities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, given the current research and risk factors for chronic disease, there is a lot we can use as general guidance, especially as we begin to venture on our path to optimal living. For example, the first 5 steps to recovery for two different people, both consuming a high-carbohydrate and low-fiber diet may be similar, if not the same. But the next 5 steps may be more individualized — and by this point — person A (or B) would hopefully be more empowered and motivated to continue on a lesser-known path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Find a buddy or accountability partner to support you on your individual journey (but remember to always celebrate shared milestones).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;8-steve-kamb-nerd-fitness&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/8-stevekamb.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F8-stevekamb-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F8-stevekamb-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F8-stevekamb-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;8 - stevekamb&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 8.) Steve Kamb — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/nerdfitness.com&quot; title=&quot;Steve Kamb&quot;&gt;Nerd Fitness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging myth the world should know entering 2016 is that relying on inspiration or motivation to get healthy just doesn&#39;t work. It might help you get started, but it won&#39;t be there over the months and months, and (hopefully) years and years of getting and staying healthy. We don&#39;t do things over the long run because they inspire us, we do them because they become habits...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wholeheartedly agree. When it comes to business, we tend to agree that ideation is followed by a business plan, which is then followed up with tangible steps and goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when it comes to health — for some bizarre reason — we tend to get stuck in the ideation phase (setting our goals), and then we get discouraged when we fall off. Though inspiration and motivation are important drivers to take action, they may not be enough to create long-lasting sustainable changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Get clear on your health goals.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Be specific. Write out your 1-month, 3-month, 6-month and 1-year goals — and besides each goal, make note of why the goal is important to you. Repeat this until they become your natural habits and then move on to the next, even bigger step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;9-marion-nestle-ph-d-m-p-h-food-politics&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/9-marion-nextle.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F9-marion-nextle-240x300.jpg&amp;width=240&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 240w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F9-marion-nextle-240x300.jpg&amp;width=240&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 240w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F9-marion-nextle-240x300.jpg&amp;width=240&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;9 - marion nestle&quot; width=&quot;240&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 9.) Marion Nestle, Ph.D., M.P.H. — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/foodpolitics.com&quot; title=&quot;Food Politics&quot;&gt;Food Politics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“If I had one thing to teach the world, it would be that larger portions have more calories. If you want to lose weight, the best way to do it is to eat less (smaller portions!).”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that excessive eating is a culprit of obesity and disease — and that weight loss can be achieved in fasting states — I would be mindful about generalizing too much when it comes to portion control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two things are far more important than the total amount of calories in a food: quality and nutrient density. For example, a small plate of fries cannot be supported as being better than a giant green salad. For many people struggling to lose weight, moving to a more nutritious (free from deep-fried and refined sugar) macronutrient-balanced diet can be the best strategy for weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;10-rich-roll-rich-roll-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/10-rich-roll.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F10-rich-roll-300x224.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F10-rich-roll-300x224.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F10-rich-roll-300x224.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;10 - rich roll&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;224&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 10.) Rich Roll — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/richroll.com&quot; title=&quot;Rich Roll&quot;&gt;Rich Roll Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging health myth of 2016 I would like to disabuse people of is the notion that “Butter Is Back” and that eating a high fat diet is healthy. Do not be fooled by the array of recently published books and so-called “health experts” supporting this supposition. It is preposterous, irresponsible and unsupported by true nutrition research…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Monounsaturated fat — as a health food — has actually been understood and appreciated for years, along with the negative effects of hydrogenated fats and trans fats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s the consumption of saturated fat that seems to be a common area of debate and misunderstanding within the scientific community, particularly around the consumption of coconut oil and grass-fed butter — two of the best examples of saturated fat today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I agree that pop culture can blow health trends out of proportion and lead to serious consequences, this particular trend has a strong scientific basis and is supported by many key opinion leaders in the field. There is strong evidence suggesting that people can reduce their risk for heart disease by eating fewer carbohydrates and more dietary saturated fats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This way of eating has also been linked to a reduction in body fat and overall weight. The medium-chain fatty acids (MCFAs) in both coconut oil and butter can also increase energy and metabolism through their unique metabolic feature, which has contributed to the popular use of these products in the biohacking and productivity-hacking community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;em&gt;Express caution on the consumption of hydrogenated or trans fats, which do have a negative impact on your fat levels.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;11-mark-bittman-mark-bittman-website&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/11-mark-bittman.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F11-mark-bittman-300x233.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F11-mark-bittman-300x233.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F11-mark-bittman-300x233.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;11 - mark bittman&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;233&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 11.) Mark Bittman — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/markbittman.com&quot; title=&quot;Mark Bittman&quot;&gt;Mark Bittman Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“One myth, with two parts: a.) we need to eat A LOT of protein, and b.) that protein is only found in animal flesh. That&#39;s what I&#39;d like to get rid of...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An excessive intake of protein is a far greater problem than low protein consumption, especially for those of us who are eating an inflammatory diet (one that is heavy on packaged foods and refined carbohydrates).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these cases, heavy protein consumption can amplify the growth of cells and even override the body’s ability to kill those cells that have been damaged (i.e., cancerous cells). Another reason we want to be mindful of our protein consumption is that our body naturally converts excess protein to glucose through a process called gluconeogenesis. For those of us who are trying to keep blood sugar levels down or reset our sensitivity to insulin, it’s important for us to keep this notion in mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another important point is that it’s unnecessary to ingest a complete protein in one sitting. Our bodies are more intelligent than we’ll ever understand; they are able to utilize and recycle consumed amino acids across a number of hours to keep our bodies functioning properly. Because of this, we actually end up with far more protein than we think, especially considering the variety of amino acids found in non-meat sources, like produce, legumes, nuts, seeds, and superfoods like spirulina.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;12-natalie-jill-natalie-jill-fitness&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/12-natalie-jillv3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F12-natalie-jillv3-204x300.jpg&amp;width=204&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 204w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F12-natalie-jillv3-204x300.jpg&amp;width=204&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 204w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F12-natalie-jillv3-204x300.jpg&amp;width=204&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;12 - natalie jillv3&quot; width=&quot;204&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 12.) Natalie Jill — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/nataliejillfitness.com&quot; title=&quot;Natalie Jill Fitness&quot;&gt;Natalie Jill Fitness&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging health myth I wish the mainstream world knew is that &amp;quot;diet&amp;quot; foods are good for us. Anytime you replace &amp;quot;fat&amp;quot; with fat-free or &amp;quot;sugar&amp;quot; with sugar-free we end up with chemical junk…”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I wholeheartedly agree with the power of unprocessed, natural foods and the avoidance of processed “machine poo”, I do caution the consumption of sugars altogether, whether artificial or natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sugars from fruit, as an example, can be responsible for poor health symptoms like chronic fatigue, mood imbalances, diabetes, and yeast overgrowth. Rather than position the recommendation to steer clear of diet foods, I’d prefer to focus on opportunities to empower people to better understand how their systems respond to all foods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My advice&lt;/strong&gt;: Write in a journal about your levels of energy and how you feel before and after food consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;13-jennipher-walters-and-erin-whitehead-fit-bottomed-girls&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/13-fitbottomed-girls.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F13-fitbottomed-girls-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F13-fitbottomed-girls-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F13-fitbottomed-girls-300x200.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;13 - fitbottomed girls&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;200&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 13.) Jennipher Walters and Erin Whitehead — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/fitbottomedgirls.com&quot; title=&quot;Jennipher Walters and Erin Whitehead&quot;&gt;Fit Bottomed Girls&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The most sabotaging health myth we hear time and time again is that you have to &amp;quot;diet&amp;quot; to lose weight. Diets do not work. If they did, there wouldn&#39;t be a million of them out there! Instead, focus on making small healthy tweaks to your day, day after day, to build healthy habits...”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I agree that an ideal place to begin your health journey is by making small tweaks and getting some easy wins to build momentum and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s not a good idea to vilify the word diet and turn it into the “bad guy”. Diet has a broad meaning covering all intentional nutrition patterns — some good, some bad. For certain people, a diet is the equivalent of a quarterly cleanse or reset with the intention of clearing damaged cells, toxins, and improving nutrition. The side effect is often controlled weight loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fasting is another form of dieting. It is often practiced with the intention of improving long-term health, extending life expectancy, and of course, losing weight. I personally don’t see anything wrong with well-designed weight loss and detoxifying diets — assuming the person adopting it is clear on their goals and limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;14-tony-horton-tony-horton-life&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/04/14-tonyhortonv2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F14-tonyhortonv2-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F14-tonyhortonv2-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 300w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fblog%2F_drafts%2Fimages%2F14-tonyhortonv2-300x300.jpg&amp;width=300&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;14 - tonyhortonv2&quot; width=&quot;300&quot; height=&quot;300&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 14.) Tony Horton — &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1871/tonyhortonlife.com&quot; title=&quot;Tony Horton&quot;&gt;Tony Horton Life&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;The myth that lasting physical, mental and emotional health comes in the form of a pill, a quick fix, or some one-dimensional workout program. This misnomer is common sense to anyone who lives a healthy lifestyle, but most folks still looking for the fountain of youth are stuck in the merry-go-round of fad after fad — just hoping or wishing that something is going to change...&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preach the truth, Tony!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Slow and steady wins the race. It’s important to guide people towards the path of optimal living by speaking their language and helping them grasp and achieve the most accessible health hacks for them. Good health is a lifelong commitment and journey — once people are on the path, they’ll be able to understand this notion more clearly with confidence and motivation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you can see, these responses are being fueled by a passionate fire of their own. And a lot of these responses contradict what’s being preached by social media, the status quo, and society at large.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So you might be wondering this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“What the heck is the right answer to living a healthy, optimal lifestyle?!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this is going through your mind right now, you seeker of truth, then congratulations — you’re beginning to ask the golden question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no “one-size-fits-all” approach or quick-fix magical solution. The honest answer — which you may not like hearing — &lt;strong&gt;is there are MANY answers&lt;/strong&gt;; what works for some doesn’t necessarily work for others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I highly encourage you to take the time to do your research and experiment with what feels right for you. There is an entire world of information out there with the exact answers you’re seeking… the tough part is separating the fluff from the facts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember — &lt;strong&gt;listen to your body, be gentle with your mind, and do what “feels” right to your soul&lt;/strong&gt;… for these will always be your best guides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But before you go, let me challenge you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading this article, how can you level-up your health game? What areas of your life are you blindly following advice from “health experts” without understanding how it truly works (or IF it even works)? What new tip or hack might you be inspired to learn about and implement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s time to rise up and be better than the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You’re destined for an abundance of health, love, and child-like happiness&lt;/strong&gt; — your breakthrough is just one simple moment away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>What&#39;s your movement? (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1764/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/id-1764/</id>
    <content type="html"></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are you being real with yourself? (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/real/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/real/</id>
    <content type="html"></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Are you the best version of you? (draft)</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/_drafts/best-version/" />
    <updated>2025-08-21T12:19:12Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/_drafts/best-version/</id>
    <content type="html"></content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Changemaker Formula  - a transformative 30 day smoothie challenge</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/the-changemaker-formula-smoothie-challenge/" />
    <updated>2021-01-11T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/the-changemaker-formula-smoothie-challenge/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“The only constant in life is change”-Heraclitus.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite our inherent desires to be and feel healthy, the majority of us are overcome with stress and confusion before we ever get the chance to try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was there once upon a time, and it was an urgency that led me to change. I thankfully came out stronger and healthier, but it’s not fun to be the only one on this side. I won’t stop until we are collectively healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Changing our lifestyles is not easy. However, making micro-adjustments to certain aspects of our lifestyles might be a little easier to chew on. One of the quickest ways I know to feel better is to focus on changing our first meal of the day—our breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I always say that every day we have another chance at a reset. The first few hours upon waking can make all the difference. It’s an opportunity to replenish your rested system with fuel in the form of nutrition and water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was suffering from fibromyalgia and irritable bowel syndrome, I was overwhelmed with all the things I needed to do to clean up my diet and lifestyle and address all of my symptoms—specifically my digestive issues (chronic constipation, insta-bloating) and chronic pain.  Then I happened upon the wonderful world of unsweetened smoothies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;unlock-your-health-potential-with-smoothies&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unlock Your Health Potential with Smoothies&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I like them to call them pre-chewed food, and because the blender takes care of most of that chewing, we can give our stressed-out digestive systems a break and help our bodies access all that nutrition. You are what you absorb, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you know me you’ll know that I have worked hard to build a case for the smoothie lifestyle—one that follows a simple formula takes little time to prepare and is extremely good for you and our planet. This is key.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, I started Global Smoothie Day in 2015 to give my advocacy a platform and explore creative ways to help more and more people around the world onboard this ultra-rewarding lifestyle. In 2020 I published a beautifully designed smoothie recipe e-book and onboarding guide. You can download it for free &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/global-smoothie-day/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;the-changemaker-formula-4-weeks-of-super-drinks&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Changemaker Formula: 4 weeks of Super Drinks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
<<<<<<< Updated upstream
=======
&lt;p&gt;If you’re just starting out and wish to further educate yourself, you should read the e-book. If you’re already inspired and want to start experimenting in a safe way, I recommend my &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thechangemakerformula.com/&quot;&gt;Changemaker Formula 30-day smoothie challenge.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
>>>>>>> Stashed changes
&lt;p&gt;The way I see it: Smoothies are the new fast food, except unlike regular fast food, smoothies recharge your body with vitamins, minerals, phytonutrients, fiber, healthy fats, and protein. Basically everything you need to feel energized, poop well, and restore your health, without getting in the way of your busy lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How It Works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You’ll hear from me, your accountability partner, first thing in the morning, nearly every day in your inbox. I’ll give you a recipe (2 servings over 1-2 days) based on the ingredients you’ve picked up and I’ll send you some nutritional facts and inspiration to feed your curious mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-it-s-priced&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How It’s Priced&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve priced it at &lt;strong&gt;$5.99&lt;/strong&gt; because I know the bigger investment for you is in the high-quality ingredients and the change in your lifestyle. I don’t want the price of this 4-week challenge to be a barrier for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-it-includes&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What it Includes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you sign up, check your inbox! Check your spam if you don’t see it. Right away, you’ll start receiving emails with easy shopping lists that include produce and diverse superfoods that you can pick up online or in your favorite health food store. You’ll need to buy, borrow or dust off your blender, too. Each email will be infused with health tips and inspiration so that you feel excited to play in the kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In total, you’ll get 15 smoothie recipes to experiment with. Keep in mind that even though you may not have access to all the superfoods mentioned in the shopping lists, it’s okay! These are meant to inspire you, not overwhelm you. They are add-ons to the base recipe, and you should feel free to use your own creativity to complete the smoothie to your liking. This will of course get easier over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;start-now&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start Now&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re feeling ready to join right now, do it! Share it with a buddy or loved one too. Accountability rocks. Register here:  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thechangemakerformula.com/&quot;&gt;http://www.thechangemakerformula.com&lt;/a&gt; and if cost is a barrier, please contact me and I’ll enrol you for free.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why I Joined Forces with Canada’s Premier Functional Medicine Clinic as a Toxicity and Lifestyle Management Practitioner</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/centre-for-advanced-medicine/" />
    <updated>2020-12-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/centre-for-advanced-medicine/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If you know me by now, you understand my belief in and commitment to the integrative healthcare model, one that encompasses conventional western medicine and traditional or holistic healing practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past decade, I’ve immersed myself in working on solving different pieces of the healthcare puzzle, from health data management to the commercialization or business of scientific research, to working directly with individuals seeking alternative healing methods, to help educate and empower them to re-design their lifestyles with a renewed focus on clean and conscious living.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My PhD in Pharmaceutical Sciences, and specifically, molecular toxicology, nutritional biochemistry, and the toxicity of the Western Diet, has equipped me with deep knowledge on the impact of environmental toxins on the human body, and the potential for high doses of select nutrients (eg. antioxidants—quercetin, glutathione, resveratrol, green tea, vitamins B, C, and D) to not only lower but also reverse the damages associated with toxicity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Truth be told, much of my nutrition and lifestyle medicine experience came from my own learning (I’m a nerd and I’m proud of it!), my deep investment into personal development, and my 15+ years healing journey recovering from chronic inflammatory disease, fibromyalgia, irritable bowel syndrome, the emotional trauma of losing my dad to cancer, and the ancestral traumas that my lineages endured, both known and unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, my certification and training in integrative nutrition and holistic health did gift me with a giant library of diverse and up to date resources for me and my clients, and a community of health coaches and integrative health advocates to learn from and exchange questions and ideas with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, it also gave me the courage and confidence to build a practice as an integrative health coach, scientific wellness educator, and now, practitioner at &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://advancedmedicine.ca/rhea-mehta/&quot;&gt;Canada’s premier Functional and Integrative Medical Clinic&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Centre for Advanced Medicine (CAM); and its sister clinic, The Canadian Centre for Integrative Medicine (CCIM).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;why-am-i-so-excited-to-announce-my-joining-of-this-clinic&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why am I so excited to announce my joining of this clinic?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve shared this in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/scientific-wellness/integrative-health-coaches-hold-a-critical-position/&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt;, and I’ll share it again now: the future of healthcare is integrative and collaborative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal scenario is for practitioners spanning conventional and traditional healthcare to come together to discuss and deliberate on patient cases, and offer diagnoses and protocols from the position of whole-body medicine and care.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAM and CCIM are 100% doing this!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a true honor to be joining forces with the clinics and focusing on my specialty of Environmental Awareness and Lifestyle Management, and leaving it to other practitioners to share their expertise in functional medicine, herbalism, psychotherapy, hormone therapy, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s become clear that my services fit nicely with the functional medicine root cause-driven model of care, and so my plan for now is to work very closely with my colleague and mentor, Dr. Leigh Arseneau, Functional Medicine Practitioner, and Educator, Naturopathic Doctor, and the Founder of these clinics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-differentiates-cam-from-other-private-integrative-health-clinics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What differentiates CAM from other private integrative health clinics?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, CAM uses the functional medicine model to integrate conventional and traditional healing modalities, to help patients both manage, prevent, and recover from the disease. The fact that the clinic has a strong focus on both modern evidence-based medicine and ancient healing methods already differentiates it from the majority of integrative health clinics, which typically have a stronger focus on holistic healing methods and often lack speciality services from medical doctors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The functional medicine model of care considers the whole life of the patient, and in a disease context, it looks at the origin, onset, and development phases of the disease, rather than simply focussing on symptom-based treatment and therapy. For example, if you have diabetes, the clinic’s model of care will address the key causes of disease, which are generally lifestyle triggered, as well as the endpoint.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practitioner-patient relationship is also unique in that the patient is encouraged to look inwards and share from the depths of their heart, which is often where much of the pain resides.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the functional medicine framework, the patient is invited to target their symptoms and situation from several different perspectives, with the intention of healing the roots of disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;clinic-services&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clinic Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Centre for Advanced Medicine is an integrative medical clinic that uses the functional medical model to treat chronic and complicated health problems, as well as help healthy patients optimize performance and quality of life. CAM’s functional medical approach uses cutting-edge diagnostic tests, evidence-based nutritional interventions, and innovative treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a practitioner, I’m able to refer my patients to related supplemental services and therapies, such as intravenous therapy, lifestyle genomics, psychotherapy, and mental health support services, and both in-house and third-party diagnostic tests to help investigate the root causes of chronic conditions. I can also recommend nutritional protocols for my patients, as I currently do in my private practice, in this case working with the best in class nutraceutical companies across North America.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;intravenous-therapy&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intravenous Therapy:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAM uses advanced IV nutrient therapy which delivers higher doses of and more bio-available nutrients to the body in order to speed up healing and recovery. IV therapy can be recommended for those living with existing chronic conditions, and can also be used to support longevity, energy, and recovery after a period of stress (related to travel, work, life).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Intravenous therapy delivers amino acids, micronutrients, plant extracts, and other useful biological agents directly into the bloodstream. This is proposed to be a more effective method of delivering nutrients to the body compared to oral forms of nutritional supplementation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personally, I’m an IV therapy enthusiast and use it to help me recover after traveling or periods of extreme stress, or as part of my quarterly biological tune-up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;lifestyle-genomics&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lifestyle Genomics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lifestyle genomics uses DNA testing to analyze one’s potential genetic limitations and susceptibilities. The practitioner will review and analyze one’s DNA data and make personalized recommendations on nutrition, exercise, and other self-care practices based on the patient’s unique genetic makeup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;specialty-testing&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Specialty Testing:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simple blood test might not be that accurate when looking at the potential root cause indicators of chronic diseases, such as evidence of toxicity (heavy metals, mold, solvents, etc), nutritional inefficiencies or deficiencies, or evidence of other foreign invaders, such as parasites, viruses, and bacteria. These types of tests generally are not available through conventional medicine, which is not designed to address the root causes of chronic disease.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAM stresses the use of the highest quality validated tests that measure one’s serum, urinary and salivary samples for more detailed information on one’s health status. Samples are collected and sent via CAM to reputable labs across North America who work with these speciality diagnostic testing companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CAM is also equipped to perform several in-house testing procedures, such as Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis or BIA (cellular health and metabolic rate), Heart Rate Variability or HRV (stress), Urine Indican (gut health), Zinc Tally (zinc status), Koenigsberg test (adrenal stress), and many more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-in-touch-with-cam&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Get in Touch with CAM&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re based in Toronto or the Greater Toronto Area and you’re feeling underserved and exhausted by the one-size-fits-all conventional medical approach, do reach out. Now that services are mostly online, CAM can work with folks outside of the GTA, so if you’re Ontario based, don’t hesitate to give them a call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Feel free to email me directly at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:dr.rhea@livingrhea.com&quot;&gt;dr.rhea@livingrhea.com&lt;/a&gt; with your inquiries or contact the wonderful humans at CAM with your questions. Call them at &lt;a href=&quot;tel:905-655-7100&quot;&gt;+1-905-655-7100&lt;/a&gt; or email them at &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ccim@advancedmedicine.ca&quot;&gt;ccim@advancedmedicine.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Why We Would All Benefit from Consuming Medicinal Mushrooms</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/benefit-from-medicinal-mushroom/" />
    <updated>2020-11-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/benefit-from-medicinal-mushroom/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;picture&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/avif&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fpages%2Fimages%2Fmedicinal-mushroom.jpg&amp;width=757&amp;format=avif&amp;via=transform 757w&quot;&gt;&lt;source type=&quot;image/webp&quot; srcset=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fpages%2Fimages%2Fmedicinal-mushroom.jpg&amp;width=757&amp;format=webp&amp;via=transform 757w&quot;&gt;&lt;img loading=&quot;lazy&quot; decoding=&quot;async&quot; src=&quot;https://example.com/.11ty/image/?src=content%2Fpages%2Fimages%2Fmedicinal-mushroom.jpg&amp;width=757&amp;format=jpeg&amp;via=transform&quot; alt=&quot;Medicinal Mushrooms for health and wellness&quot; width=&quot;757&quot; height=&quot;504&quot;&gt;&lt;/picture&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fungi have been around on Earth for more than 2 billion years, pre-dating animal and plant life. While some species are poisonous, there are a number of species with superpowers that can nourish, heal, and boost the health of humans and our shared planet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The latter are referred to as medicinal mushrooms. These fungi deliver more healing than meets the eye. Superficially, they are loaded with vitamins and minerals, which is surely one of their superpowers. However, they also have bioactive components that they release to protect themselves during times of stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These bioactive ingredients have incredibly therapeutic, and even magical healing properties, which historically led to their use as medicines in several ancient cultures around the world for the past several millennia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&quot;today-through-the-scientific-method-we-are-now-learning-that-medicinal-mushrooms-may-be-one-of-the-most-multi-modal-healing-medicines-on-the-planet-with-the-potential-to-treat-heal-and-prevent-some-of-the-most-complex-chronic-conditions-of-our-time&quot;&gt;Today, through the scientific method, we are now learning that medicinal mushrooms may be one of the most multi-modal healing medicines on the planet, with the potential to treat, heal, and prevent some of the most complex chronic conditions of our time.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;a-brief-history-of-medicinal-mushrooms&quot;&gt;A Brief History of Medicinal Mushrooms&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned, mushrooms have been consumed and celebrated by human beings in ancient traditions spanning the globe for thousands of years, as both food and medicine. Saharan aboriginal tribes in North Africa are said to have used mushrooms in 9000 BC. Mushroom consumption was also referenced in Tibetan and Siberian shamanism and Buddhism, as well as in spiritual texts from Mexico, Guatemala, and Mesoamerica.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Out of 150,000 known species, 14,000+ have been identified, with ~2,000 categorized as edible. More recently, medicinal mushrooms have been used in Traditional Chinese and Japanese Medicine for the management of conditions including cancer, diabetes, disorders of the heart, liver, and brain, digestive issues, longevity, and vitality. Some mushrooms have even been clinically validated in the East and approved as an adjunct therapy for certain cancers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;modern-science-has-its-eyes-on-medicinal-mushrooms&quot;&gt;Modern Science Has Its Eyes on Medicinal Mushrooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given the reverence of mushrooms in traditional therapies across the world, modern scientists are looking to validate and document the healing methods. The past three decades have seen growth in the scientific analysis of medicinal mushrooms, into a field now known as mycology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This field investigates the nutritional (culinary) and therapeutic (medicinal) value of many compounds extracted from a range of mushroom species. Given the vast therapeutic potential of medicinal mushrooms, several other fields of science, including toxicology, immunology, and neuroscience, are also deeply investing in medicinal mushroom research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Holistic health practitioners are also on the mushroom train, promoting the preventative and therapeutic health benefits of the most well-known medicinal mushrooms to their clients and communities. These include chaga, reishi, lion’s mane, cordyceps, turkey tail, shiitake, and maitake.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While research is still in its infancy, positive results from cellular, animal, and some clinical data, plus the historical reference to frequent multi-functional use in ancient traditions across the world, have equipped several holistic health advocates with the confidence to both use and promote the safe use of these powerful mushrooms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;therapeutic-components-of-medicinal-mushrooms&quot;&gt;Therapeutic Components of Medicinal Mushrooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medicinal mushrooms have three distinct parts:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mycelium&lt;/strong&gt; – stores food and energy to produce a mushroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fruiting body&lt;/strong&gt; – the mushroom itself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spores&lt;/strong&gt; – produced by the mushroom&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nutritionally, medicinal mushrooms are enriched with fiber, protein, unsaturated fatty acids, minerals, and vitamins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are also several bioactive compounds that make these mushrooms the medicinal superpowers they are. These include polysaccharides, terpenoids, phenolics, flavonoids, and carotenoids.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits-of-medicinal-mushrooms&quot;&gt;Benefits of Medicinal Mushrooms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Research on the bioactive compounds of medicinal mushrooms has demonstrated several therapeutic activities, including:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-cancer and anti-tumor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immune system-regulating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-viral and anti-bacterial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-inflammatory&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brain health-boosting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-obesity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-aging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wow—right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;immune-system-regulation&quot;&gt;Immune System Regulation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Probably the most critical therapeutic benefit of our time is the immune system–boosting effects of these mushrooms. Some species have been shown to increase the activity of the body’s natural defense system, as well as the removal of damaged cells.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given immune system dysfunction is a key factor in certain cancers, mushrooms could play a significant role in the generation of future anti-cancer drugs — with lower toxicity than current options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;potential-source-of-vitamin-d&quot;&gt;Potential Source of Vitamin D&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another critical benefit: vitamin D. It’s essential for immune health, bone health, blood pressure regulation, and nerve function, but not produced by the body. While we mostly get it from sun exposure or supplements, mushrooms may act as a great natural source of vitamin D.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s still unclear whether the vitamin D absorbed through mushrooms is in the form most bioavailable to humans. But given the limited sources, including a diversity of mushrooms in the diet is a smart idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-go-to-daily-health-supplement&quot;&gt;My Go-To Daily Health Supplement&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using medicinal mushrooms for over a decade for health and healing. I started with chaga in tincture and tea form and noticed improved energy and clarity. I then moved on to reishi, cordyceps, and lion’s mane, which I continue to use today for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immune system health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brain health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced detoxification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Anti-inflammatory support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Longevity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re curious to explore the world of medicinal mushrooms, I recommend choosing an organic supplier with third-party testing, good manufacturing practices, and sustainability protocols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m proud to be an affiliate of Vancouver-based company &lt;strong&gt;Qi Traditions&lt;/strong&gt; because they’re transparent about their methods, use top-notch processes, and compostable packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&quot;https://qitraditions.com/?ref=6qd23azmupo_livingrhea&quot;&gt;Check out their resources and products here&lt;/a&gt; (you’ll get 10% off, and full disclosure: I get a small commission).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only affiliate myself with the best — right now that’s &lt;strong&gt;Qi Traditions&lt;/strong&gt; and the stress-reducing wearable-tech company &lt;a href=&quot;https://example.com/blog/apollo-clinically-validated-wearable-device/&quot;&gt;Apollo Neuro&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re not sure which mushrooms are best for you, you can fill out a quick quiz on the Qi Traditions website to receive a personalized recommendation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have questions? Leave them in the comments below — I’d love to help.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Apollo: A New Clinically-Validated Wearable Device that improves your resilience to stress</title>
    <link href="https://example.com/blog/apollo-clinically-validated-wearable-device/" />
    <updated>2020-11-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/blog/apollo-clinically-validated-wearable-device/</id>
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to tell you about a groundbreaking stress reducing and sleep enhancing wearable device that actually works!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s called Apollo Neuro, and it was created by Psychiatrist and Neuroscientist Dr. David Rabin, MD, PhD. It has been clinically validated to improve heart rate variability, a key metric of stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dr. Rabin noted that touch was overlooked in stress management, despite its ability to trigger safety to the body and lower stress. Through research, Dr. Rabin found that certain waves of vibration can bring our bodies and minds back to balance fast. And they can do this while improving our heart rate variability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Apollo device was therefore designed by Rabin and team to mimic touch through these waves of vibration, thereby stimulating the trust and safety center of the brain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The result: activation of the “rest and digest” parasympathetic nervous system, restoring balance in the body and mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is unique in that it is considered a safe and non-addictive way to feel better over both the short and long term, by training your brain to bounce back more quickly from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/scientific-wellness/how-to-feel-great-every-day/&quot;&gt;stressful states&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-apollo-works&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How Apollo works&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrap the Apollo device on your wrist or ankle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select the mode on the mobile app that best reflects your status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personalize the duration and intensity of the vibrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;here-are-the-7-modes-to-choose-from&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the 7 modes to choose from:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Energy and Wake Up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social and Open&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clear and Focused&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rebuild and Recover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meditation and Mindfulness&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Relax and Unwind&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sleep and Renew&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;benefits&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;increased-heart-rate-variability&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased Heart Rate Variability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We all experience stress to varying degrees. Some of us experience quite debilitating symptoms as a result of the stress in our lives, such as headaches, anxiety, pain, frustration, lethargy, and the list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress converts external situations into internal reactions, and can have a long-term impact on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.livingrhea.com/scientific-wellness/secrets-of-healthy-living/&quot;&gt;health&lt;/a&gt; and quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While there exist tools and practices to manage stress, such as meditation, breathwork and consuming an anti-inflammatory diet, as well as certain medications and nutritional supplements, Apollo works to optimize your stress response with little input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apollo is as simple as wearing a band to mitigate stress. It doesn’t get easier than that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Specifically, it improves heart rate variability (HRV). If you’re new to HRV, essentially, the higher your HRV, the better you should feel. With improved HRV, you feel calm, relaxed, and better overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;better-sleep&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Sleep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stress also disrupts sleep. A stress-free system is generally associated with healthy sleep. With Apollo, there is a sleep mode you can select which actually helps you improve sleep in real-time through this gentle vibration technology. It doesn’t just improve sleep in real-time, but it also helps you sleep better over the long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;improved-focus&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improved Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focus is one of our greatest challenges today due to the many distractions, notifications and inputs---especially while so many of us are at home right now. And if we’re stressed or tired, it makes it even harder to concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Focused attention is necessary for high performance. Apollo gets us back into a focused flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clear and focus setting on the Apollo app is one of my favorites. When it’s on and vibrating, I feel like in flow for hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;get-10-off-with-my-code&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://apolloneuroscience.pxf.io/c/2535242/916509/12331&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get 10% Off With My Code&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve gotten so much out of this device, that I signed up to become an affiliate. Now I can get you 10% off—which is helpful, since it’s a few hundred dollars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, I believe it’s worth the investment considering how much money we spend on other therapies and treatments to help us reduce stress.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those therapies might help in real-time, but they don’t continue to make us better and more resilient to the stress response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s nothing else quite like Apollo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you get one, please share your feedback with me! I’d love to hear how it’s worked for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
  </entry>
</feed>